Guide to the John Bates Clark Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Unpublished Scholarly Materials, circa 1865-1936
  - Subseries II.3: General Notes, circa 1865-circa 1935
    - Class Notes and Notebooks
      - Roman and Medieval History (in German), circa 1874-1877 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Annotated Published Works
      - Articles, 1907, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Ricardo, David. THE FIRST SIX CHAPTERS OF THE PRINCIPLES OF POLITICAL ECONOMY AND TAXATION. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1909. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Loose Research Notes
      - General Notes, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
      - General Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Agriculture, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Book Ideas, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Capital, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Civilization and Economies, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Conservation and Environment, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - "Crises," undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Distribution, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Dynamics, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Gambling, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Immigration, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Interest, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Labor and Its Relationship with Capital, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Land, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - "Law of Accumulation," undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Legislation, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Money/Currency, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Politics, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Prices, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Productivity, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Profit, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Railroads and Transportation, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Ricardo's Theories, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Socialism, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Statics, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Stocks, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Tariffs, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Technology, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Trade and Markets, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Trusts and Competition, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Unions and Strikes, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Value, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Wages, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - War, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Wealth, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Subseries II.4: Administrative, Course, and Professional Materials, 1899-1936
    This subseries contains the small volume of material in the John Bates Clark Papers relating to Clark's work outside of research and class. Items range from administrative material related to teaching to pamphlets of the New York Peace Society to reports and records relating to Clark's occasional informal work with the federal government.
    - Administrative Records and Course Materials, undated, 1905-1913 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Commission from Theodore Roosevelt to Attend a Conference on Trusts on Behalf of the State of New York, 1899 (Folder 14-O-1)
      (oversized)
    - Committee on Industrial Relations Pamphlets, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Government Price Study: "Milk: A Study of the Ways of an Industry, Part I," by Irene Till, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Government Price Study: "Milk: A Study of the Ways of an Industry, Part II," by Irene Till, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Government Price Study: "The Price of Waste Paper," by Florence Till, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Government Price Study: "The Price of Whiskey," by Albert Abrahamson, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - New York Peace Society Memorandum: "Economic War Against War," 1918 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - New York Peace Society "Statement of Purposes," 1921 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Pujo Committee Articles, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Report on American Economics Association's 25th Anniversary, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Report on "Minneapolis Conference of Employer and Employe," 1902 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Report to Mayor on Teacher's Salaries in New York City, 1909 December 28 (Folder 14-O-1)
    - Republican National Committee Questionnaire, circa 1918-1921 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Smith College Trustee Materials, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Statement on Trusts Made Before a Senate Committee, 1912 December 11-12 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Series III: Published Scholarly Materials, circa 1880-1936
  Series III comprises material related to the extensive bibliography of published work produced by John Bates Clark. It includes drafts of articles and book chapters, a selection of published material, and a number of newspaper clippings concerning John Bates Clark and his work.
  - Subseries III.1: Drafts, circa 1880-1930
    This subseries consists of a mix of hand-written and typed drafts for a number of the many articles and books written by John Bates Clark, including notable works such as The Philosophy of Wealth (1885) The Essentials of Economic Theory (1907) and A Tender of Peace (1935). While most of the drafts are complete, note that there are a substantial number of unidentified manuscript fragments and individual chapters to longer works.
    - Analysis of the 1924 Presidential Election, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Biography," circa 1910s (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Capital and Its Earnings," circa 1888 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - "The Cause of Peace in Light of Current Events," 1913 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Chapters and Outlines for a Book on War, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Chapters for a Book on War and Economy, circa 1914-1930 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Concerning the Nature of Capital," 1907 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Contributions to Economic Dynamics," undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Dealing With Trusts by the Natural Method," circa 1890s (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Defining the Term "Capital," 1890 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Definitions of Terms in Economics and Political Economy, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Distribution Under Natural Law," undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "The Economic Costs of War," 1915 December 17 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Economic Interpretation of War," undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "The Economic Situation," undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "The End of the War: A Study of the Probabilities," 1916 November (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "The Ethics of a Single Tax," undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Existing Alliances and a League of Peace," 1915 June 11 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "A Federal Commission on Industrial Relations," 1912 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Forces of Economic Progress, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "Forgotten Points in the War Debt Discussion," 1926 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "The Genesis of Capital," 1893 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "Labor Union Paper Plan," undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Land and Labor Under Natural Economic Law," circa 1893-1895 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Lessons in Political Economy," 1922 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Letter to the Editor Concerning Public Works Projects, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Letter to the Editor Concerning Tax Legislation, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Man's Relation to Other Animals," undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Manuscript Fragment Regarding Land and Interest, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Manuscript Fragment Regarding Rent, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Manuscript Fragment Regarding Strikes, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Manuscript Fragments, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Manuscript Fragments for ESSENTIALS OF ECONOMIC THEORY, circa 1907 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Manuscript Fragments Regarding War, 1921-1922 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Manuscripts Regarding Capital, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript Regarding Capital and Wealth, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript Regarding Competition, 1883 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript Regarding Competition and Monopoly, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "The Minimum Wage," undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "The Modern Appeal to Legal Forces in Economic Life," 1894 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Monopolies and the Effect on Prices, Wages, and Interest," undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "The Moral Basis of Property in Land," circa 1882-1895 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Note for Insert and Outside Reader's Comments [Regarding ESSENTIALS OF ECONOMIC THEORY], undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "The Origin of Interest," undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "A Peace Measure with a Recoil," undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - THE PHILOSOPHY OF WEALTH, "Introduction to the Japanese Edition, circa 1895 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "The Possibility of a Scientific Law of Wages," circa 1889, (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - "Reform or Revolution," undated, 1913 (Box 11, Folder f 15)
    - Response to "MacFarlane" Regarding John Bates Clark's Views on Rent, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Shall We Surrender to Monopoly?," undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Sherman Act, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "Social Justice Without Socialism," 1913 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "Spiritual Economics," circa 1880 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "A System of Monopolies," 1920 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - "The Theory of Economic Progress," undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "The Theory of Freight Charges," undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "The Theory of Interest," undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "The Total Depravity of the Economic Man," undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Trust Articles Published in the REVIEW, 1892 February 18-April 7 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Two Theories of Wages, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - "The Unit of Wealth," circa 1896 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Unspecified Chapter Materials, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Wages and Interest as Specific Products of Labor and Capital," "Plan of Conclusion," "Note," and Two Loose Pages on Economic Development in China, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "War and Democracy," undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Subseries III.2: Published Articles, 1878-1935
    This subseries represents the large volume of published articles written by John Bates Clark that are in the collection. It begins with a small selection of individually-bound works and a complete bibliography of John Bates Clark's published work. With those few exceptions, the bulk of the material in this subseries survived in the form of scrapbooks of unknown origin. While the scrapbooks have been disassembled for preservation purposes, the material they contained has remained cohesive and in the original numbered order. Each scrapbook contains a table of contents, and a master index and bibliography for the seven numbered scrapbooks appears before Scrapbook One.
    - Loose Pamphlets
      - "Bibliography of John Bates Clark," 1931, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - "Ein Altes Prinzip in Neuer Zeit," 1928 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - "The Government of Alien Races by the United States.. .," 1899 February (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "The Scholar's Opportunity," 1898 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "A Universal Law of Economic Variation," with Handwritten Notes, 1894 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Article Scrapbooks
      - Scrapbook Index and Bibliography of Included Works, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Scrapbook 1, 1881-1910, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
      - Scrapbook 2, 1886-1911 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Scrapbook 3, 1878-1911 (Folder 14-O-1)
        (oversiezed)
      - Scrapbook 4, 1877-1912 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Scrapbook 5, 1878-1916 (Folder 14-O-1)
      - Scrapbook 6, 1913-1922 (Folder 14-O-1)
      - Scrapbook 7, 1910-1924 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - "Clark--Essays on Economics, 1877-90," with Handwritten Notes, 1890 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Subseries III.3: Reviews and Clippings, 1882-1936
    This subseries contains reviews and notices (primarily from newspapers) of Clark's published works, as well as clippings of articles which were written about Clark.
    - Reviews, 1882-1936 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, circa 1900-1923 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Press Release for A TENDER OF PEACE, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Biographical Materials, 1848-1957 (1868-1939)
  Series IV consists of material related to John Bates Clark's personal life, his death and legacy, and Clark family history and genealogy.
  - Subseries IV.1: Personal Documents, 1848-1937
    This subseries holds a range of personal material from all facets of John Bates Clark's and the Clark family's lives, and is particularly useful in giving a glimpse of Clark's wide-ranging interests outside of academic life. The earliest materials are an 1851 letter written by Clark's great-grandfather, Daniel Clark, and an 1857 diary belonging to Clark's father, John H. Clark. Representative items include two patents held by John Bates Clark, the manuscript of a story he wrote for his children, and several account books. There are also several folders of documents related to Clark family history and genealogy.
    - Academic Documents, undated, 1873 (Folder 14-O-1)
    - Account Books, 1869, 1905, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Articles about John Bates Clark from REVIEW OF REVIEWS and the FINANCIAL CHRONICLE, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Biographical Manuscripts, undated, 1934-1937 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Clark Family History and Genealogical Research, 1851-1910 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence Regarding and a Facsimile of E.L. Ipsen's Portrait of John Bates Clark, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Diary of John H. Clark, 1857 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Diary and Almanac of John Bates Clark, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Documents Related to Carleton College, 1885, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Financial Records "of Value as Souvenirs," 1848-1869 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - THE HISTORY OF THE CLASS OF 1869 AMHERST COLLEGE, "LIGHT," 1889 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lyrics for "International Hymn" written in 1896 by George Huntington, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript of a Children's Story, "Sir Peter Longlegs," by John Bates Clark, circa 1920-1930 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Memorial for George Huntington, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Articles Regarding John Bates and Myra Almeda Clark's Sixtieth Wedding Anniversary, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Notes for Birth-day Speech," undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Passports of John Bates Clark and Charlotte Clark, 1872 (Folder 14-O-1)
    - Patents Held by John Bates Clark, 1868-1869, 1896 (Folder 14-O-1)
    - Poem Manuscript: "Hard by the City Hall There Dwells," undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Program for a Speaking Contest, with Enclosed Card, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Subseries IV.2: Materials Concerning the Death of John Bates Clark, 1938-1957
    This subseries contains several areas of interest. The first is a collection of obituaries and memorials to John Bates Clark. Next are documents related to the publication of John Bates Clark: A Memorial (1938). This small book was written and published by the children of John Bates Clark after his death, and a copy of the book appears in this series. The third component of this subseries is a memorial scrapbook of unknown origin (though it was likely assembled by Myra Almeda Smith Clark shortly after her husband's death), which has been disassembled for preservation purposes. The order of the items from the scrapbook (including general papers, obituaries, and correspondence) has been retained, as has the cover. Please note that additional correspondence concerning John Bates Clark's death can be found in Series I. Finally, this subseries contains a few individual items related to John Bates Clark's death and legacy, most notably a copy of the program from his memorial service at St. Paul's Chapel on the campus of Columbia University.
    - Memorials and Obituaries for John Bates Clark
      - Journals Featuring Obituaries of John Bates Clark, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Memorials to John Bates Clark, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Obituary Clippings, 1938 March (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Documents Regarding JOHN BATES CLARK: A MEMORIAL
      - JOHN BATES CLARK: A MEMORIAL, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Documents, 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Lists of Recipients, 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Reviews and Press Notices,1939 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - John Bates Clark Memorial Scrapbook
      - Frontmatter and Cover, undated (Folder 14-O-1)
      - Obituaries, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Other Material Regarding John Bates Clark's Death and Legacy
      - Documents Regarding John Bates Clark Papers, undated, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Memorial Service Program, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Pamphlet on Mourning, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Series V: Photographs, 1920-1938
  Series V is composed of three picture-postcards sent by Myra Almeda Smith Clark to John Bates Clark and two matted photographs of John Bates Clark's interment service.
  - Interment of John Bates Clark, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Postcards Sent by Myra Almeda Smith Clark to John Bates Clark, 1920-1921 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- List of Correspondents
  - Abbott, Lyman
  - Adams, Henry Carter
  - Agger, Eugene Ewald
  - Anderson, Benjamin M.
  - Andrews, E(lisha) Benjamin
  - Armstrong, M.A.
  - Bacon, George Wood
  - Bacon, Selden
  - Balfour, --
  - Ballantine, William Gay
  - Banks, Enoch Marvin
  - Barnett, George E.
  - Barns, W.E.
  - Barret, Thomas, Towles
  - Beckhart, Benjamin Haggot
  - Bell, James Washington
  - Bellamy, Edward
  - Bemis, Edward Webster
  - Benedict, Roswell A.
  - Bingham, Millicent Ford
  - Boening, Otto von, Baron
  - Bo¨hm-Bawerk, Eugen von
  - Bonar, James
  - Bostable, C.F.
  - Brand, Katherine E.
  - Brearley, J.A.
  - Brentano, Lujo
  - Brewster, William Tenney
  - Brown, Arthur Judson
  - Brown, T. Edwin
  - Bryce, James, Viscount Bryce
  - Burgess, John William
  - Burnham, Michael
  - Burton, Marion LeRoy
  - Burton, Theodore E.
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray
  - Butz, Alvin J.
  - Carey, Robert L.
  - Carnegie, Louise Whitford (Mrs. Andrew)
  - Cary, Mildred and Julia
  - Catlin, Warren B.
  - Caveruo, Julius H.
  - Chalmers, Allan Knight
  - Choate, Washington
  - Church, Brooke (Mrs. John A.)
  - Clancy, W.P.
  - Clark, Alden Hyde
  - Clark, Charlotte Huntington (Mrs. John H.)
  - Clark, Eleanor Phelps (Mrs. Frederick H.)
  - Clark, J. Edmund
  - Clark, John Bates
  - Clark, John Maurice
  - Clark, Mary Lawrence
  - Clark, Myra Almeda Smith (Mrs. John B.)
  - Continental Guaranty Corporation
  - Cutler, Anna A.
  - Dalla Volta, Richard (Riccardo)
  - Dawe, Grosvenor
  - Denslow, Van Buren
  - Devine, Edward Thomas
  - Dewey, Davis R.
  - Dill, James B.
  - Dorfman, Joseph
  - Douglas, Paul H.
  - Dublin, Louis I.
  - Duggan, Stephen
  - Dunbar, Charles Franklin
  - Dyer, Walter A.
  - Echetoun, Fannie H.
  - Edwards, Edward Junius
  - Ely, Richard T.
  - Ely, Robert Erskine
  - Emerick, Charles Franklin
  - Emerson, Anna Seelye
  - Emerson, Ellen T.
  - Ewing, Maria Dunlap
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt
  - Feiler, Arthur
  - Fetter, Frank A.
  - Finley, John H.
  - Fisher, Irving
  - Folwell, William W.
  - Forbes-Robertson, Ian
  - Francis, David R.
  - Franklin, Fabian
  - Garman, Charles E.
  - Gates, Merrill E.
  - Gay, Edwin F.
  - Giddings, Franklin H.
  - Gide, Charles
  - Gildersleeve, Virginia Crocheron
  - Gillett, Frederick H.
  - Gilman, Daniel Colt
  - Ginn & Co., Publishers
  - Ginzburg, Eli
  - Gladden, Washington
  - Graham, Frank D.
  - Green, Margaret Foster Lyman (Mrs. Charles B.)
  - Griffis, S.B.
  - Gunton, George
  - Hadley, Arthur T.
  - Hale, Mary T.
  - Hale, Robert L.
  - Hardon, Cora Burr (Mrs. H.W.)
  - Harriss, C. Lowell
  - Hauge, Gabriel S.
  - Hazen, Charles Downer
  - Hepburn, A. Barton
  - Hill, Paul A.
  - Hill, William Bancroft
  - Hirst, Francis W.
  - Hirst, Gertrude
  - Hollander, Jacob H.
  - Holt, Hamilton
  - Honda, M.
  - Howson, Roger
  - Hubbard, Elbert
  - Hughes, Charles Evans
  - Hunt, Francis M.
  - Hunt, Rockwell Denis
  - Hyde, Charles C.
  - Iles, George
  - Irvine, Alexander
  - Jacbostein, Meyer
  - James, Edmund J.
  - Jenkins, Annie E. Huntington
  - Jenkins, Emily (Mrs. Harry)
  - Johnson, Alvin S.
  - Johnston, Alexander
  - Jones, Alice Gale
  - Jordan, David Starr
  - Jordan, Mary A.
  - Keppel, Frederick P.
  - Kimball, George C.
  - Kinley, David
  - Kinosita, Yetaro
  - Kitahara, Yoshimo
  - Knox, Raymond C.
  - La Fontaine, H.
  - Laidlaw, Harriet Burton
  - Lamont, Florence
  - Lamson, Charles M.
  - Lancaster, Helen Converse Clark (Mrs. Henry C.)
  - Lancaster, Henry Carrington
  - Lazard, Max
  - Levah, S.
  - Levermore, Charles H.
  - Lindsay, Samuel McCune
  - Lord, Herbert G.
  - Loria, Achille
  - Low, Annie Wroe Scollay (Mrs. Seth)
  - Lowenthal, Esther
  - Lyman, Elizabeth Huntington Clark (Mrs. Frederick W.)
  - Lyman, Frederick Clark
  - Mackenzie, Kenneth
  - McKinney, Ethelyn
  - Malin, Patrick Murphy
  - Mansfield, Helen C.
  - Marburg, Theodore
  - Marshall, Alred
  - Marshall, Mary Paley (Mrs. Alfred)
  - Martin, Caro Taylor
  - Mayo-Smith, Richmond
  - Michael, Emil
  - Miller, Frank J.
  - Mills, Frederick C.
  - Mitchell, Wesley C.
  - Miyajima, Tsunao
  - Moore, Henry L.
  - Moore, John Bassett
  - Morganthau, Henry
  - Morrow, Dwight W.
  - Morrow, Elizabeth Reeve Cutter (Mrs. Dwight W.)
  - Morse, Anson D.
  - Morse, Margaret Duncan (Mrs. Anson D.)
  - Mund, Vernon A.
  - Munsterberg, Hugo
  - Neilson, William Allan
  - Norton, Thomas H.
  - Olds, Marion E. Leland (Mrs. George D.)
  - Otte, Gerhard
  - Padan, R.S.
  - Paine, Lyman M.
  - Palgrave, Robert Harry Inglis
  - Panio, Fannie
  - Pareto, Vilfredo
  - Patten, Simon N.
  - Pegram, George B.
  - Perry, Bliss
  - Phelps, Mary Booth (Mrs. Charles H.)
  - Philippovich, Eugen
  - Plimpton, Anne
  - Plimpton, George A.
  - Potter, William P.
  - Powell, William P.
  - Proffitt, Charles G.
  - Pupin, Michael Idvorsky
  - Rankin, J.S.
  - Rignano, Eugenio
  - Robinson, Frederick B.
  - Robison, Mary C.
  - Rodgers, Anna S.
  - Rogers, E.H.
  - Rogers, Lindsay
  - Root, Elihu
  - Rowe, Leo S.
  - Royal Swedish Academy of Science
  - Sabine, Jane D. Kelly (Mrs. Wallace C.)
  - St. John, Martha Everett (Mrs. Charles E.)
  - Sakatani, Yoshiro, Baron Sakatani
  - Sayles, Lita Barney
  - Schumacher, Hermann
  - Schumpeter, Joseph
  - Schuyler, Eugene
  - Schwiedland, E.
  - Scott, James Brown
  - Scuola, Positiva, La
  - Seelye, Julius H.
  - Seelye, Laurenus Clark
  - Seligman, Edwin R.A.
  - Shaw, Albert
  - Shepherd, William R.
  - Shirras, G. Findlay
  - Shotwell, James T.
  - Slocum, William F.
  - Smiley, Albert K., Jr.
  - Smith, Gertrude Huidekoper (Munroe-)
  - Smith, Harry de Forest
  - Smith, Munroe
  - Smith, Preserved
  - Spencer, J.O.
  - Springer, Julius (Verlag)
  - Stanfield, Otto M.
  - Stein, L.V.
  - Stewart, Gertrude D.
  - Stillman, Frances
  - Stimson, Henry A.
  - Stimson, Philip M.
  - Sullivan, Mark
  - Suranyi-Unger, Theo
  - Taft, William Howard
  - Takei, D.
  - Tarbell, Ida M.
  - Taussig, Frank W.
  - Taylor, Horace
  - Thomas, Paul B.
  - Todd, David
  - Townsend, Charles E.
  - Trask, O.C.
  - Tuttle, Charles A.
  - Viallate, Achille
  - Villey, Edmond
  - Von Tobel, Rudolf
  - Walker, Charles Swan
  - Walker, Francis Amasa
  - Walras, Leon
  - Warne, Colston E.
  - Warren, Schuyler N., Jr.
  - Warren, William F.
  - Washington, Booker T.
  - Welling, Lucy Lord (Mrs. Brenton)
  - Westergaard, Harald
  - Westgren, A.
  - Whitaker, Albert Conser
  - White, Horace
  - Whitin, E. Stagg
  - Whittin, Robert H.
  - Wieser, Friedrich Frieherr von
  - Wilbrandt, Robert
  - Wilson, Woodrow
  - Woodbridge, Frederick J.E.
  - Wright, Carroll D.
  - Young, Allyn A.